910-23 Hollywood Ave. Toronto, ON M2N7L8 Cell: (416)566-0128 II Email: youhan.guan@gmail.com Portfolio Website: youhanguan.com

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Youhan Guan is a creative coder, interaction designer and UI/UX designer exploring in various digital media fields; familiar with the major aspects of the field and further specializing in user interface / experience design, interaction design and researching on multiple HCI fields.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Specialized Honour B.A. in Digital Media

May 2016

Lassonde School of Engineering, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Research Assistant**

March 2015 - Present

York University, Brian Alliance, Toronto, Ontario

• Research, design and develop a tabletop touch display user interface for data visualization and query using tangible objects and touch gestures.

# **User Interface Design Intern**

June 2014 - August 2015

IBM Canada, Toronto, Ontario

- Designed the wireframe and visual mock-ups of cloud applications for multiple products, such as IBM Watson and Incentive Compensation Management Desktop/Web.
- Designed the wireframe and visual of a multi-platform application for demo in IBM Vision 2015.
- Created series of user interface visual elements details for various applications.

# Web Designer and Developer

May - August 2013

Aoyee International, Toronto, Ontario

- Designed and constructed firm's official site based on the Drupal system within a team.
- Worked as the main graphic designer of Hainan Airline 20th Anniversary Celebration.
- Designed the logo for Canada-China Business Engagement Association.

## PROJECT AND COLLABORATION

AR / VR / Web / Mobile Application Design and Development:

## **Encounter**

January - April 2016

- Encounter is an interactive installation which explores the coexistence of human and a virtual artificial life ecosystem through Spatial AR and Tangible AR means.
- A spatial co-located 3D graphics data visualization and query system is developed using Unity and Vuforia SDK, for both Android and iOS devices.

Blink November 2015

 A mixed reality game designed and developed for Leap Motion 3D Jam using Leap Motion gesture sensor and head mounted display, featuring a gesture controlled AR UI interface.

# **Virtual Gallery**

January – April 2014

 A virtual reality gallery which transmit the users into 3D virtual worlds of world-famous paintings. Through Oculus Rift head mounted display, user can navigate and explore the virtual worlds generated in painting-specific styles. Als were developed to enhance the interactions. Food R Us December 2015

 Designed and developed an e-commerce website using APACHE Server based on MVC structure, coded in Java, HTML and JavaScript using Normal CSS. Featuring full functionality of B2C online-shopping, analysis, user authentication, and a B2C-B2B middleware providing purchase order report files to food supplier.

Rank 1<sup>st</sup> place in the course EECS 4413, Building eCommerce Systems.

For more interactive media projects, please visit: <a href="http://youhanguan.com">http://youhanguan.com</a>

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES**

**Design Director** 2013 – 2015

York University Chinese Students and Scholars Association (YUCSSA)

- Contributed design skills for each events.
- Tasks allocation and scheduling. Holds workshops and to tutor Adobe Photoshop.

# **Programming Tutor**

2014 - 2015

Digital Media Student Association (DMSA) at York University

 Helping and tutoring students in Digital Media program with courses involving coding in Java.

### **ACHIVEMENTS / AWARDS**

- Dean's Honour Roll in 2011, 2014, 2016
- Projects been exhibited and presented in Digital Media Showcase (2012 -2016), I/O
  Exhibition of Interactive Art (2013), Surface Normal (2014), LevelUp Showcase Toronto at
  Design Exchange (2015, 2016), Pan Am / Parapan Am Games at York (2015), ISO: Student
  Night at The Power Plant (2015), Computational Beauty at Interaccess (2016).
- 3<sup>rd</sup> Place in Intel IoT Roadshow Toronto (2015).
- Golden Key International Honour Society member since 2015.

### **SKILLS**

Operating Systems

Experience using Windows-, Mac- and UNIX- based systems.

## **Programming**

- Java, JavaScript, HTML, HTML5, CSS, C#, MIPS, Unix Shell Scripts.
- IBM DB2 database management system and programming SQL.

## Design

- Professional in Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, Premiere, and Axure.
- Professional in illustration (both digital and hand-drawing).

## Other Skills

- Physical Computing Installations using Arduino, Intel Edison.
- Professional in Unity3D, 3DsMax, Google SketchUp, Lotus.

## **LANGUAGES**

English and Mandarin

Fluent, advanced reading and writing.